JET MARTIN

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Email: jetamartin@gmail.com Phone: 619-384-1721 LinkedIn: jet-martin-b769a11/ GitHub: https://github.com/jetamartin

SUMMARY

Certified Software Engineer with 3 years of professional software development experience and 15 years of product management experience. Current focus is full stack web development specializing in React/Node.js and Python/Flask software stacks with an interest in building modern, clean, high-quality, customer-centric software solutions.

SKILLS

LANGUAGES / WEB TECHNOLOGIES: JavaScript, Python, jQuery, Ruby, Java, HTML5/CSS

FRAMEWORKS: React, Node.js, Express, Flask, Rails, Cordova, Bootstrap

DATABASE: SQL, NoSQL (MongoDB, CouchDB, PouchDB)

TOOLS / UTILITIES / METHODOLOGIES: Git/GitHub, Jasmine/Jest Testing tools, RESTful API, RWD, Test Driven Development

RECENT PROJECTS

<u>Tennis-Central</u> (https://tennis-central.surge.sh/)

A full stack web app (React/Node.js) that connects tennis players with similar skill levels & availability for match play

- Server implements full RESTful API and utilizes Sequelize ORM for accessing PostgreSQL database
- Frontend: SPA using React, Bootstrap for styling, Formik for form handling and Yup for form field validation
- Backend: Express/Node.js with PostgreSQL DB, Password hashing via bcrypt, User auth using JWT, RESTful API
- Source code and project README.md can be found @ https://github.com/jetamartin/tennis-central/

<u>Almost Karaoke</u> (https://almost-karaoke.herokuapp.com/)

A full stack web app (JavaScript/Flask/Python) that displays YouTube Music Videos alongside the video's lyrics.

- Leverages Google's YouTube API and Genius's Music Lyrics API as data sources
- Frontend: HTML/CSS and JavaScript with Bootstrap styling
- Backend: Flask/Python with PostgreSQL DB. Password hashing via bcrypt. User auth using JWT, RESTful API
- Source code and project README.md can be found @ https://github.com/jetamartin/not-so-karaoke/

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

Springboard Software Engineering Career Track

2020 - 2021

• 9-month, 700+ hours of hands-on course material, with 1:1 industry expert mentor oversight, and completion of 4 in-depth portfolio projects. Mastered skills in front-end web development, back-end web development, databases, and data structures and algorithms. Tech stacks React/Node.js and Flask/Python.

IBM, Software Engineer, Palo Alto, CA

1984 – 1987

- Designed and developed Transport layer networking protocol for an OSI-based intrabank messaging system
- Led architectural design and code reviews for Transport Layer and related project component
- Implemented a full set of unit and integration tests for the Transport layer

FULL EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

MobiSenz Solutions, Founder, San Diego, CA

2013 - 2015

Software/hardware company whose mission was to create "smart" solutions by combining intelligent sensor technology and intelligent software developed to run on smart phones and mobile devices

- Created market segmentation model to identify market opportunities for a wearable sleep analysis solution
- Interviewed potential customers in the targeted market segments to capture their product requirements
- Completed 3-year market forecasts for two target market segments to analyze revenue potential of target markets

Mitchell International, Senior Director of Product Management, San Diego, CA

2006 - 2010

- Directed Mitchell's Medical bill review product offerings which accounted for revenues of \$50M/year
- Supervised team of 5 Product Managers and 2 systems operation specialists
- Conceived and successfully implemented first Product Training track for customers attending Annual Customer Summit

BakBone Software Inc, Director of Product Management, San Diego, CA

2003 - 2005

Global supplier of Data Protection software for mid-size businesses with annual revenues of \$50M

- Directed and mentored a team of Product managers that was responsible for all of BakBone's product revenue
- Led customer engagements to determine their business needs and created product specifications to satisfy those needs
- Authored business plan to extend product suite to include real-time data protection solutions leading to \$5M acquisition

Iomega, *Product General Manager, Software Solutions*, San Diego, CA

2002 - 2003

- Managed Iomega's data storage software solutions business unit
- Established product line strategy, product roadmap and product specifications
- Negotiated OEM license with Toshiba to bundle backup software on their laptops resulting in 10% revenue increase

EMC (Division of Dell Corporation), Director of Product Management, Palo Alto, CA

1999 - 2002

- Business line responsibility for backup and recovery storage management platform and Disaster Recovery products
- Developed product specifications for a web-based storage management console reducing customer management cost by 20%
- Managed a team of Product managers, Product Marketing Managers and Technical Marketing Engineers

3Com Corporation, *Product Line Manager*, Santa Clara, CA

1996 - 1999

- Increased 3Com's Fast Ethernet Hub market share by 4% to a market leading 34% market share and \$100M revenue run rate
- Initiated and executed marketing and promotional campaigns for distribution channel that increased YOY sales by 17%
- Spearheaded business plan and secured executive buy-in to pursue new market resulting in creation of a new SAN division

Hewlett Packard, Tech Consultant / Strategic Product Planning Manager, Cupertino CA

1987 - 1996

- Collaborated with HP Dev team to customize HP products to fit needs of strategic customer opportunities
- Recipient of HP Excellence Award for crafting solution enabling HP to win \$30M contract to supply Walmart with Unix servers
- Defined Network Product Strategy for Unix Server Division and orchestrated \$75M networking product portfolio

IBM, Software Engineer, Palo Alto, CA (See description in Relevant Experience)

1984 - 1987

EDUCATION

University of Georgia

BS Computer Science

GPA 3.6 - Cum Laude graduate. Honors program

San Diego Continuing Education - Web Development Program

- Front End Web Developer 1 Certificate Fundamentals of Web Dev and Design (360 hours/18 weeks)
- Front End Web Developer 2 Certificate JavaScript and jQuery for Web Dev (360 hours/18 weeks)
- Mobile App Development Certificate- Cross-platform mobile solutions using Cordova (84 hours/12 weeks)

LEARN Academy Coding Bootcamp

• 3-month, full stack Web development program (HTML/CSS JavaScript, Ruby on Rails, PostgreSQL)